<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.ianswope.Calix</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <name>Calix</name>
  <summary>Swipeable calendar with cloud sync</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Calix is a native calendar for Linux, built with GTK4 and libadwaita.
      It syncs both ways with Google Calendar, iCloud, and any CalDAV server
      (Fastmail, Nextcloud, Radicale, and more), and keeps everything in a
      local SQLite store so the app stays fast and works offline.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Swipeable month, week, and day views</li>
      <li>Two-way sync with Google, iCloud, and generic CalDAV accounts</li>
      <li>Drag events to move or resize them, with a live snapped preview</li>
      <li>Create events by clicking or right-clicking anywhere on the grid</li>
      <li>Show or hide individual calendars from a native sidebar</li>
      <li>Passwords and tokens stored in the system keyring, never in files</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.ianswope.Calix.desktop</launchable>

  <developer id="com.ianswope">
    <name>Ian Swope</name>
  </developer>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/ianswope/calix</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/ianswope/calix/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/ianswope/calix</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Month view</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ianswope/calix/v0.2.0/docs/screenshots/month.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Week view</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ianswope/calix/v0.2.0/docs/screenshots/week.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#99c1f1</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#1a5fb4</color>
  </branding>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>
          Calix now syncs automatically in the background — on launch and
          every 15 minutes — so connected calendars stay current without a
          manual refresh. An expired Google sign-in surfaces a clear reconnect
          prompt instead of failing quietly, and this release fixes several
          issues across sync, storage, and iCalendar handling.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>
          Week and day grids gain a zoom control and a live current-time
          marker, event titles show in full as a hover tooltip, and the window
          now matches the active Omarchy theme's colors. This release also
          scopes CalDAV account identity to the (username, server) pair and
          fixes seven audit findings across sync, storage, and drag handling.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>
          Generic CalDAV account support with two-way sync, drag to move and
          resize events in the week and day grids, and right-click event
          creation.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
